阿勇
A-Yong!
你去哪里啊 阿勇
A-Yong! Where are you going?
截至一月二十二日二十四时
As of midnight Jan. 22
国家卫健委 收到
the National Health Commission received
国内二十五个省区市
from 25 provinces and municipalities
累计报告新型冠状病毒
reports of new corona virus infection
感染的肺炎确诊病例五百七十一例
a total of 571 confirmed cases
其中重症九十五例
of which 95 cases are critical
我们叫了四个小时的车
We've waited four hours
都没有人敢去
No one would pick us up
一个二个的都往后躲
Everyone's avoiding us
你们这些医生
You doctors
为什么要冲到前头 替别人卖命啊
How come you are always on the front line?
反正老子不信邪
Whatever, I'm not scared
生死由命 富贵在天
Life or death, fame and fortune, it's all fate
紧急通知 武汉长江隧道将暂时关闭
Emergency alert : the Yangtze Tunnel will be temporarily closed
请在现场工作人员的指挥下 有序撤离隧道
Please follow directions and evacuate calmly
我跟你说了
I told you
不要当着客人的面和酒店纠缠
don't argue in front of the guests
先换一个
Just find another hotel
换一个能够接受武汉人的酒店
that would accept guests from Wuhan
星级价位同档次
in the same price range
赶快把他们两个搞回来
Get the two of them back quickly
君君还有三个多月就要生了
Junjun is due in three months
不老老实实在屋里养胎
She should have stayed home
挺个肚子满世界耍
not traveling to the other side of the world
你个当妈的
You are her mother
还助纣为虐
now you are helping them stay away?
你莫吵了好不好
Stop yelling
我这世界各地有十五个团 都困住回不来
I have 15 tour groups who are stuck right now
你让我处理下工作好不好
Let me deal with this mess
你搞清楚一点 是五千 不是五百
Hey let's be clear, it's 5000, not 500
刘亚兰
Liu Yalan
老子跟你说正事儿
I am talking to you!
你不要吵了 好不好
Please don't yell
个板马
God damn it!
什么时候了 你还添堵
What the hell are you doing?
你不会开车回家去
Go home if you don't know how to drive!
你说什么
Are you talking to me?
你下来 来来来 你下来
Get out of the car, come on, get out!
你就像个苕
You idiot
妈
Mom
哎 我在超市
Yes, I'm at the market
菜不多了
There's hardly anything fresh left
藕 藕
Lotus root, lotus root
等一下
Hold on a minute
没抢到藕
The lotus roots are all gone
没抢到就没抢到
It's all right
赶快回来
Just come home
外面不安全
It's not safe out there
好 好
Okay okay
受疫情影响
Due to the outbreak
离汉通道即将关闭
all transportation in and out of Wuhan will be shut down
现场迎来了大批退票人员
Many passengers are demanding refunds
具体情况
More details ......
对不起
Excuse me
我姑娘从深圳回来还可以吗
Can my daughter still come back from Shenzhen?
对不起
Excuse me
非常抱歉
I am sorry
十点以后所有离汉通道将会关闭
all transportation will be shut down by 10am
她不是离汉的 她是回来
She's not leaving Wuhan, she's coming back in
建议不回汉
It's best that she doesn't
啥时候开呢
When will transportation resume?
明天 后天 大后天总得有个时间吧
Tomorrow? The day after? There's got to be a date
非常抱歉现在还在等通知
I am sorry we must wait for further notice
暂时不知道
We don't know at the moment
您需要退票吗
Do you need a refund?
我不退怎么办
What else can I do?
好 您稍等
Okay, please wait for a moment
对不起啊 对不起
I am sorry, I am sorry
对不起
I am sorry
您的票已退
Your ticket is canceled
钱会全额退还到您的账户
and you'll be refunded in full
还不全额 还扣钱
Of course in full! It's not my fault
谢谢你啊师傅
Thank you so much sir
我也不知道 给你多少合适
I don't know how much to pay you
这个时候不谈钱 不谈钱
Don't worry about money, not now
你们下班
When you finish working
我们最近不回去了
We won't be going home for a while
保护家人
need to protect our families
对对对
Yes you are right
你别下车
Please don't get out of the car
这个病毒蛮狠
The virus is really tough
千万注意
Please be careful
谢谢
Thank you
这不行 这不行
No, no, please don't
你晚上回去 好好消下毒
Make sure to disinfect before going home
快走 快走
You have to hurry
谢谢了啊
Thank you
谢谢
注意防护啊
Take care of yourself
阿勇
A-Yong!
马上封城了 你到底跑哪儿去了
The city is shutting down, where are you going?
赶快回家
Hurry home
武汉市新型冠状病毒感染的肺炎疫情
Given the situation of new corona virus in Wuhan
防控指挥部发布通告
the Emergency Response Center announces
自二零二零年一月二十三日十时起
as of 10 o'clock on January 23
武汉市全市城市公交 地铁 轮渡
Wuhan public transport, including buses, subways and ferries
长途客运暂停运营
all operations are suspended
无特殊原因 市民不要离开武汉
all residents are asked not to travel except for special circumstances
机场 火车站 离汉通道暂时关闭
Airports and train stations will also be closed temporarily
城都封了 哪个去送啊
The city's shut down, who are doing the deliveries?
兄弟
Hey Man
看一下
Take a look
拿着拿着
Take this, take this
来 支持一下
Help me out here
啥东西
What's this?
英雄帖
Flyers for volunteers
广招天下英豪
Heros are needed
勇哥啊
A-Yong
封城了还发传单
Why bother? The whole city is shut
九八年特大洪水
Remember the Flood of '98?
南北夹击 倾泄三镇
Wuhan was completely under water
洪水来了我们要干嘛
What did we do then?
要跑
Run away?
鬼扯
Bullshit
跑不脱
There was nowhere to run
哎 勇哥我看一下
A-Yong, let me take one
病毒就像洪水
The virus is just like the flood
医生在守江堤
Doctors are protecting the dam
我们要干什么
What can we do?
扛沙袋
We can help carry sandbags
来来来
Come on, people
拿着
Pass these around
这是什么
What's this?
来 张意博
Come on, Zhang Yibo
你看一下
Take a look
来 帮我传一下
Pass it around
江城大疫 危在旦夕
Our hometown is under siege
英雄不问出处
You too can be a hero
但肯拔刀相助
If you are willing
现招募天下豪杰
We are looking for heros
第一 单身独居的优先
First, singles preferred,
无后顾之忧
no family concerns
愿意签的 欢迎
If you sign up, welcome
不愿意签的
If you don't
也不丢人
no pressure
第二 戴口罩消毒
Second, always wear a mask and disinfect
逞能犯苕是作死
Stupidity is not heroism
第三 微信群不准聊天
Third, no chitchat in the group
违者除名 永不录用
You'll be kicked out if you break the rules
本人自愿签下承诺书
I am signing under my own free will
无论生死 义无反顾
prepared to die for the cause
奋战到底 绝不服输
never give up, never surrender
这是哪个写的 政府
Who drafted this? The government?
政府
The government
你级别有点高啊
Your aim is a little high
我
I did!
你
You?
那怎么算钱呢
How do we get paid?
志愿者
Volunteers
救灾的解放军要钱吗
Are soldiers paid for disaster relief?
你又瞒着嫂子逞能犯苕
You must be doing this behind your wife's back
我跟你说
I tell you
你再这样下去
If you keep this up
嫂子让你跪搓衣板
Your wife is going to make you suffer
人在江湖 靠什么
For a man, what's the most important thing?
义字当先
Courage
病毒我都不怕 我怕老婆
I am not afraid of the virus, or my wife
我跟你说
I tell you
你要去 自己去
You go ahead if you want to
我还要赚钱养娃
I have my kid to think about
我不去白送死
I'm not dying for the cause
莫笑
Don't laugh now
事情搞大了 哪个都跑不脱
If the virus rages on, no one can escape
来
Come on
来 拿着拿着
来哈
Come on
喂
Hello
是红星连锁店的李老板 是吧
Are you Mr. Li, the owner of Red Star Grocery chain?
我是志愿者阿勇
I am volunteer A-Yong
今天不是年三十嘛
Today is New Year's Eve
我们想给医务工作者
We want to organize a holiday dinner
组织一些年夜饭
for the health workers
你看你能不能帮忙
Would you help us?
你是志愿者
You? A volunteer?
我还劳动模范呢
Don't try to swindle me
再敢打来
Believe me
老子让你在公安局看春晚信不信
I'll report you to the police
你好
Hello
是江南医疗品商店
Is this Jiangnan Pharmacy?
我是志愿者阿勇
I am Volunteer A-Yong
请问一下 你们可不可以
Please may I ask for a favor
滚远点
Stop calling
滚远点 滚远点
Go away, go away
喂 爸爸
Hi, Dad!
喂 你妈的电话打不通
Hi! I'm trying to reach your mom
她怎么不接电话呢
How come she won't answer?
她把你拉黑了
She's blocked your calls
你跑出去那么长时间
You were gone for so long
妈妈都要被你气死了
Mom is really upset
爸爸 你搞什么去了
Dad, what are you doing?
你什么时候回家啊
When are you coming home?
我就是
I am just
做志愿者嘛
volunteering
就接送一下医护
driving doctors and nurses
做志愿者 那是做好事啊
Volunteering? That's great!
你跟妈妈说
You go tell your mom
妈 妈
Mom Mom
我爸是当英雄去了
Dad is a hero
我不说
I don't care
英雄又不缺他一个
Why does he have to be a hero?
呆头呆脑的
So stupid
他以为他的武术能打得过病毒啊
Does he think his Kungfu can beat the virus?
不说不说不说嘛 老婆
Oh please sweetheart
今天是大年三十
It's New Year's Eve
新年快乐
Happy New Year
一点都不快乐
I am not happy at all
滚一边去
Go away
兄弟
Hey man
新年快乐
Happy New Year
儿子 你在做什么啊
Son, what are you doing?
你妈消气了吗
Has Mom calmed down?
还没 她年夜饭都没吃
No, she didn't even eat dinner
墨卫侠更新了啊
Is the new installment of Superhero Mowei out?
是的爸爸
Yes Dad
你好造业啊
You are in trouble
墨卫侠拯救世界
Superhero Mowei has his girl
还有个小姐姐陪他走天涯
when he's saving the world
你得罪了我妈
You made mom mad
那就只有你一个人了
You are all alone
所以你才要帮你妈 多做些事情
I know. You should help Mom
我不在家 你不要光玩
I am not home, you are the man of the house
我没玩 我刚帮我妈洗完衣服
Yeah, I just helped her with laundry
爸爸你看
Look Dad
狗日的
You little shit
爸爸你看 这个好玩吧
Dad look at this
还不睡 小孩不能熬夜
Go to bed, it's late
快睡
Hurry
快睡觉 莫惹你妈生气
Go to bed, listen to your mother
哦
Okay
那我睡了啊
Good night
你注意安全啊 爸爸
Take care of yourself, Dad
拜拜
Bye-bye
赵虎
Zhao Hu
勇哥
A-Yong
赵虎呢
Where is Zhao Hu?
赵虎
Zhao Hu
东西拿出来
Give it back
什么东西
What?
东西拿出来 莫装
You know what, give it back!
什么东西啊
Don't know what you are talking about
我搓火
Damn it!
救援物资也可以拿
How can you steal disaster relief supplies?
蛋白粉去哪了
What happened to the protein powder?
你给我说清楚
Hey, let's be clear
谁说是我拿的了
Who told you that I took it?
我没证据 我查不到你头上
I have solid evidence
把东西拿出来
Just give it back
我不跟你计较 听到没
and I'll let it go this time
不要逼我
Don't push me
拿出来 听到没
Listen, just give it back
你放开我
Leave me alone
听到没
You heard me
放开 你放开
Let go of me
好
Alright
你说
Tell me
你要不揩油水 你脸上的N95哪儿来的
Where did you get your N95 mask then?
我脑袋系在裤腰带上了
Damn it, I am risking my life here
拿你几箱蛋白粉怎么了
What if I took a few cases of protein powder?
赵虎
Zhao Hu
天天医院里头跑啊
You go by the hospitals every day
没看到吗
Haven't you seen
医生 护士 拿命在拼哦
how the doctors and nurses risk their lives?
蛋白粉是给他们提高免疫力的
The protein powder can boost their immune system
你身强体壮的
You're strong as an ox
你拿走心不亏吗
Don't you feel guilty stealing from them?
我亏心
I feel guilty?
我天天提货送货 跑多少地方
I make daily delivery to all these dangerous places
我得见多少人
How many people do I come into contact with?
我难道不需要免疫力
Don't I need to boost my immune system too?
你别跟我胡扯
Don't talk nonsense
东西拿出来
Give it back
要不然我对你不客气听到没
Give it back or else
你还来是吧
Or else what?
给我松手
Let go of me
算了
Alright
个板马
Damn it!
我习武之人
I know Kungfu
我让你三分
I'm not going to fight you
老子不干了
I quit
什么东西啊
Who do you think you are
老子来是给你面子
I am doing you a favor
还真把自己当根葱了
You are not my boss
赵虎
Zhao Hu
你就是走
Before you go
你也把下午那批货接完再走
you are supposed to do this delivery
还代表月亮消灭你
Guardian of Justice ？
你要是再不守规矩 乱发信息
If you send this stupid message again
我代表宇宙消灭你
I am going to make you sorry
还有谁会开货车
Who else can drive a truck?
看着我做什么
What are you looking at?
后来呢
Then what happened?
后来 他有点上头
Then he got worked up
他一个黑虎掏心就冲过来了
rushed up with the "the Black Tiger"
而我嘞
And I
只是一个二字钳阳马
fought back with "the Powerful Stallion"
我借力发力 给他来了个釜底抽薪
I laid him out using his own momentum
你猜怎么样
Guess what
怎么样
What
一米九几的个子啊
He's nearly 2 meters tall
库嚓一下
Hey-yah!
就趴到地上了
flat on the ground
爸爸你好威风啊
Dad, you are cool!
你老爸 像不像你看的那个墨卫侠啊
Doesn't Dad look like your Superhero Mowei?
像 蛮像
Yes, you do!
爸
Dad
你现在干嘛呢
What are you doing now?
我在高速路口接货
I am waiting to pick up supplies at the check point
哦
Okay
儿子啊
Son
跟老爸说一下
Tell me
今年压岁钱 收了多少
how much did you get in "red envelops" this year?
我跟你商量一下
Can I ask you
你看能不能
to do me a favor?
借老爸用一下
Can you loan me
你的钱呢
your money?
哪有大人找小孩借钱的道理
How can a grownup borrow money from a kid?
谁还没个难处啊
Well everyone runs into difficulties once in while
志愿者要做贡献嘛
The volunteers are supposed to help
我就把钱都捐了
I donated all of my money
哪晓得
Who knew
我把医生的东西给搞丢了
I lost some supplies
要补上啊
I have to make up the difference
爸爸 你好夸张啊
Dad, you are too much
你把钱都捐了 又瞒着我妈吧
You donated all of your money, behind mom's back?
难怪我妈骂你到处逞强
No wonder Mom complains about you
脑壳有包
that you've lost your mind
搞什么亏什么
that you are a failure
你妈对我还是有些偏见的
Your mom is prejudiced against me
我看我妈那是火眼金睛
I think mom is really sharp
不是 我
No I
淮阳翠柳
Huaiyang Willow restaurant
是不是杭帮菜啊
is that Hangzhou style?
不是说过吗 在志愿者群里不要聊天
I said no chitchat in volunteer group
压岁钱这么多啊
That's a lot of pocket money
这是我妈让我转给你的
Mom gave me the money to send to you
眼看这都封城十几天了
The city as been shut down for days
前两天真是把我急死了
I have been so worried
这政府的防疫物资来了
Now the government sent all these
放心了
I can finally relax
等一下 等一下
Hey, hold on a moment
你看一下
Look here
我跟你说
I tell you
这些是薄的
These are thin
那些是厚的
These are thick
这些是山东来的
These are from Shandong Province
这是厚的
These are the thick ones
对 这是厚的 要分清楚
We have to keep track
然后还有生活用品
Then these are consumer goods
这些
These
还有那些 都是生活用品
and those are consumer goods too
好的 好的
Okay okay
牙刷 牙膏 毛巾
Tooth brush, tooth paste, hand towel
这是一套
these are a set
都是齐的
Everything is accounted for
所有的货 我都分类
All divided by categories
标注好了
I've marked everything
这些都是我们需要的
These are all things we need urgently
真是来得太及时了
Thank goodness they are here
也就只能做这些了
That's all we can do
这是货物的数量 你帮我签个字
The total count, please sign here
好的好的
No problem
对面的
Hey
有人没
Anyone there
出来吵个架撒
Come out, let's talk
好闷呐
So frustrating
我门口 一直在过车
There have been ambulances passing through all the time
这得多少病人啊
How many patients are there?
我这边也能看到好多救护车
I can see a lot of ambulances here too
估计是往方舱和雷神山火神山转移病人吧
They are probably moving patients to the isolation sites
老婆
Honey
我今天
Today I
我今天看到
Today I saw